A Guide to the Papers of the Fontaine-Maury Society 1910-1991
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Fontaine-Maury Society 1910-1991
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6269-l
This collection consists of ca. 200 items (1 Hollinger box).
Sharon Defibaugh
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were loaned to the University of Virginia Library by Charles E. Moran, Charlottesville, Virginia, on August 26, 1999.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the collection of the Fontaine-Maury Society, ca. 200 items (1 Hollinger box), ca. 1910-1920, 1958-1991, and undated, contains correspondence, genealogies, photographs and a scattering of financial material. Much of it concerns the founding of the Fontaine Society Lending Library, and Lawrence Fontaine LeStourgeon is the chief correspondent. The photographs include Miss Maury Fontaine (ca. 1910), Lawrence Fontaine LeStourgeon, Matthew Fontaine Maury Osbourne, Philip C. Bell, Mariah G. (Fontaine) Bell, Charles Lee Foushee, Sr. and his family, Deborah Hobbs Fontaine, William Maury Fontaine, and three pictures of gravestones.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1973, 1987-1991
- Correspondence from William Maury Morris II 1990-1991
- Correspondence 1987-1989
  re the founding of the Fontaine Society Library
- Financial Papers ca. 1989-1991
- The Fontaine-Maury Society Library 1990-1991
  List of Members
- Fontaine Reunion at Scotchtown and Richmond, Virginia 1988 Jun & Oct
- Genealogical Information ca. 1958-1989, 2 folders
  re the Fontaine Descendants
- Genealogical Information n.d.
  re Aaron Fontaine
- Genealogical Information ca. 1974-1991, n.d.
  re Lamar Fontaine
- Genealogical Information n.d.
  re the Rev. Peter Fontaine
- Genealogical Information n.d.
  re the Overton Family
- Genealogical Information 1920
  re the Prather Family
- Mailing Lists ca. 1988-1991
- Photographs 1910, 1988-1989